This domain will take us through input and output
operations. For the next few videos, we will work
with files using an app's code. Regarding gaming,
one often needs to store values in a configuration
or similar file for items such as player or game
settings. One such example is this 311-open file,
which has code that opens a file, writes to
it, and closes it on the first three lines
of the code. I have that code in this file to
ensure we have a file to work with should you
decide to run this code from any folder. By
default, this code sends files to one’s user
folder under Users. What I want to focus on is
the code on line 5. There is a variable called
message test. For that variable, we see an open
command and the name of a file to open. The r
argument opens the file in read mode. I will cover
read mode and other modes in upcoming topics. And
since we are not yet reading any content from the
file, as we are covering that in another topic,
I have a print statement on line 6 acknowledging
the file is open and I will run this code to
get that acknowledgement. The key takeaway
here is that, when opening an external file,
we want to store that action in a variable
because, as we will discover in upcoming videos,
there are many methods we can run to read
content from a file, write to the file, or
do other actions on the file. We need to know how
to open a file to do those actions on the file.